Curriculum Vitae - Everton Canez F. da Silva

Everton Canez - everton.canez@gmail.com - Version 4.5, Oct 2019

Timeline

1997		1998	2000	2001	2005	2011	2015 - present
HTMI	L	HTML	HTML	HTML	HTML	HTML5	HTML5
CSS		CSS	CSS	CSS	CSS	CSS	CSS
Javas	Script	JavaScript	JavaScript	JavaScript	JavaScript	JavaScript	JavaScript
		ASP 3.0	PHP	Java	Java	Java	Java
				PHP	JSP	JSP	Android
					PHP	PHP	Ionic
						Android	Typescript
							Angular
							NodeJS

About me

I'm a flexible easy going style with 18y+ hands-on software development experience and practical experience in web and mobile projects.

I have experience working in many teams and I have good communication skills. I know Java, PHP, Android, HTML, CSS, Javascript, working with PostgreSQL, MySQL, MSSQL and Oracle Databases for as much as I can remember. For the last 5 years I'm focusing especially in javascript technology and frameworks using NodeJS and Angular.

I like frontend and backend development, I love programming languages and I'm very committed self-learning person. I'm looking for opportunities to join a creative team in projects that could make difference in clients business value.

Full Stack Developer

Hotmedia - Web Broadcast Radio & Television Sep 2019 – Present Porto Alegre Area, Brazil

https://notreniev.github.io/resume/

Responsible for frontend and backend development in Angular and NodeJS. Also implementing automation tests using Jest and CI/CD deploy on GitLab.

Full Stack Developer

PROCERGS Aug 2011 – Present Porto Alegre Area, Brazil

In 2011, after months in a new position as Java Analyst I was invited to join a mobile/web team where I could work with all the technologies that surround it. My responsibility was research & development for mobile/web projects. That was the early days of mobile platforms. Suddenly I wasn't only a Java Analyst, Mobile and Web Developer, but also a researcher too.

In this position I was able to find new ways to solve software architecture problems, new technologies and different ways to think and solve this problems. In these almost last 9 years on it I was able to work with many different projects which led me to work with:

- JavaScript
- Typescript
- AngularJS
- Restify
- Express
- NodeJS
- Angular 2, 3, 4, 5...
- UX
- Ionic
- Cordova
- Progressive Web Apps
- RESTful APIs
- Java
- Android
- OOP
- Microservices
- Oracle, MySQL, MSSQL, PostgreSQL and MongoDB Databases

Today I work as a front-end and backend developer with teams in transit department and others areas to help improve public services.

Professional Experience

Java Analyst

PROCERGS Aug 2011 - Dec 2011 (4 months) Porto Alegre Area, Brazil

In 2011 I did for a public tender to start at a new position as Java Analyst and I passed to arrume a new position. I started working with Java/PHP/Javascript/HTML/CSS in several intern projects to solve problems for the management area who wanted to automate some processes and workflows in the company using Oracle Workflow and Java.

Some of this workflows were about implementation of ITIL (Information Technology Infrastructure Library), in disciplines like Configuration Management, Changing Management, Problems Management and so on.

Web Developer

PROCERGS

February 2005 - August 2010 (5 years 7 months) Porto Alegre Area, Brazil

In 2005 I was invited to join the Technical Operations Team. At this point I was beginning with Java/JSP for software development in one project, but in Technical Operations team I was able to work in several other projects. In some point I was responsible for maintaining 6 Java applications simultaneously, all of them communicating with each other via web services (SOAP and after a while RESTful).

By the time it was a common thing the monolithic architecture and so it was for a while. Meanwhile, I was having a good progression on my career being promoted each couple of years or so.

Technical Operations Engineer

PROCERGS

March 2000 - January 2005 (4 years 11 months) Porto Alegre Area, Brazil

In March 2000, I became a team member of the Systems Operations Department as Technical Specialist and I was responsible for developing web systems for the

company's intranet. By then I used to program a lot in ASP and had to learn more about data modelling and some Systems Analysis, providing a huge workflow for this department I was working in.

System Network Administrator

Colégio Marista Nossa Senhora do Rosário August 1998 - July 2001 (3 years) Porto Alegre Area, Brazil

Porto Alegre Area, Brazil Responsible for the IT support for school's intranet, network and website development

Call Center Agent

PROCERGS

December 1997 - March 2000 (2 years 4 months) Porto Alegre Area, Brazil

Call center attendant responsible IT support for clients of several areas like Police Department, Public Security, Water and Sewage Department and Company's Internet Provider clients.

Education

2014 - 2016

Graduate course Computer Software Engineering Universidade de Santa Cruz do Sul

2007 - 2010

University graduate Computer Software Technology/Technician Faculdade de Tecnologia SENAC-RS

Main Interests

- Javascript
- Angular
- Typescript
- NodeJS
- Open Source
- UX
- APIs
- Microservices
- Android
- Java

Soft Skills

- Committed
- Creative
- Passionate
- Proactive
- Productive
- Empathy
- Active listening
- Adaptable
- · Business focused
- Enthusiastic
- Collaborative

Organized

Personal Details

Nome: Everton Canez Ferreira da Silva

Location: Porto Alegre, RS, Brazil

Social Media: @notreniev, notreniev.github.com

Calendly https://calendly.com/evcanez

Skype: everton.canez@gmail.com **Phone:** Phone: +55 51 991120621

Portfolio

Randonneurs Brazil

This is a freelance and the latest project I'm still working on among other things. It consists in a **NodeJS** backend persisting in a **MySQL** database for Randonneurs Brazil, which is an organisation that regulates and approves brevets Randonneurs Mondiaux, the BRMs, linked to the Audax Club Parisien of cycling. This backend will serve data to an **Angular** website and a React Native app.

BMMOB

An App to help police from Rio Grande do Sul State to attend daily police reports. It was written in **Ionic Framework** with **Cordova** to run in **Android** devices. This app communicates with a **Java** (1.8) backend on **JBoss Server 7.0** to synchronize its data with several informations and photos of this reports with an **Oracle Database**.

National Address Consulting

This is a **micro-service** written in **Java** for integration with other Government applications for consuming address in Brazil as a **Java Rest API**. It helps to locate address information in the whole country based on zip code, address, city or state. This **API** was develop using **Java 1.8** running in a cluster of **JBoss Server 6.4** and **Oracle 10** Database.

PROCERGS Apps

This is an internal app store for PROCERGS company to distribute apps for clients who doesn't want to distribute their apps through oficial app stores like Google or Apple. It was written using AngularJS in Front-end, communicating with Java 1.8 REST API on backend, and persisting its data in a PostgreSQL Database.

Digital School

Project in partnership with Pontifical Catholic University (PUCRS) and Huawei to informatize school classroom processes in public schools of State of Rio Grande do Sul. Consists in synchronise classroom information through a mobile app running in an **Android** tablet and then sending all information to a **JBoss server REST API** in the backend with an **Oracle Database**.

Turismo RS

This is an **Android** app for Tourism in the Rio Grande do Sul state. It gives information about the cities, touristic points of interest, places to stay, places to eat, hotels and etc. It communicates with an PHP backend.

Offline ballot box

The popular offline ballot box is an **Android** app that consists of an electronic ballot box app to vote on citizen budget priorities, and it's persisted on a PHP backend API using a **PostgreSQL**. Its goal is to bring popular voting to areas without internet access, allowing more citizens to participate on the voting process to prioritise projects on public sector.

Voice List

This is an **Android** app briefly inspired by the GTD (Getting Things Done) concept. It's a personal project which allow users to create organised lists using their voice and manage those lists to manage tasks, prioritising between active and archived lists and also marking list items as being finished.

52 Weeks Challenge

This is also a personal project written in **Android** to help users to save money. The goal here is to save a small amount of money every week always doubling this small quantity each week until you get the amount you need to achieve your goals.

Technical Skills

Languages and Frameworks:

- Javascript
- Typescript
- Angular
- NodeJS
- Restify
- Express
- Jest
- Java
- Spring Boot
- Android
- Shell script

Databases:

- MySQL
- MSSQL
- MongoDB
- SQLite
- Oracle
- PostgreSQL

OS: OS X, Windows

Tools:

- VSCode
- Eclipse
- Git
- Bash Shell
- Gradle
- Netbeans
- Maven
- Hibernate
- Spring Tools Suite
- Jenkins
- Artifactory

https://notreniev.github.io/resume/

Language Skills

• Portuguese: Native language

• English: Fluent

Personal Interests

- My family: Father of a little girl and owned by two cats
- Music: Playing guitar, blues, rock, Eric Clapton, Led Zeppelin, AC/DC
- Movies: Star Wars, Indiana Jones, Back to the Future
- **Books:** Lord of The Rings by J.R.R. Tolkien, Eric Clapton Biography by Eric Clapton, Led Zeppelin Biography by Mick Wall
- TV Shows: The Big Bang Theory, Stranger Things, Brooklin 99, La Casa de Papel
- Programming: Frontend, UX and Backend Development
- Sports: Running, bicycle, swimming

Version 4.5 Last update 2019-10-13 21:48